Finding Aid for William M. Cary Papers, 1963-1986
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
William M. Cary Papers 1963-1986
Cary, William M.
0.75 linear ft.
Environmental education teacher at East Grand Rapids, Michigan, High School and member of the board of the West Michigan Environmental Action Council. Subject files consisting of newsletters, reports, testimonies, and printed material relating to Michigan environmental issues.
8876 Aa 2
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The papers were donated by William M. Cary (donor no. 7474 ) in August 1987.
The collection is open for research.
William M. Cary is a biology teacher at East Grand Rapids High School and an active member of the Michigan Environmental Education Association. As such, Cary has worked for the incorporation of environmental education programs in Kent Intermediate School District. From 1972-1974 Cary and colleagues developed and implemented plans for a nature walk: the Manhattan Nature Trail in Hodenpyl Woods, Grand Rapids. Cary has collected materials on a variety of environmental issues of particular interest to Michigan environmentalists, as well as printed materials of two Grand Rapids-based environmental organizations, the West Michigan Environmental Action Council, and the Center for Environmental Studies.
The William M. Cary papers consists of three-quarters linear foot of newsletters, reports, testimonies, and printed materials concerning Michigan environmental issues and groups. The collection is arranged alphabetically in one topical series. There are nine subseries, including: Center for Environmental Study, Energy Conservation, Environmental Education, Manhattan nature Trail, Noise Pollution, Nuclear Power Plants, Pesticides, Water Quality, and West Michigan Environmental Action Council, covering the years 1963-1986. The three subseries of primary interest to researchers are Environmental Education, Manhattan Nature Trail, and Water Quality as they are the most complete.
Subjects:
Cary, William M.; Conservation of natural resources--Michigan.; Environmental protection--Michigan.; West Michigan Environmental Action Council.
- Topical Files
  - Center for Environmental Study (printed material), 1971 and undated, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Energy Conservation (printed material), 1975-1986 (Box 1)
  - Environmental Education
    - manuscripts, 1969-1976 (Box 1)
    - manuscripts, undated (Box 1)
    - printed material, 1972-1983 and undated (Box 1)
  - Manhattan Nature Trail, 1972-1977 and undated (Box 1)
  - Noise Pollution (printed material), undated (Box 1)
  - Nuclear Power Plants, 1970-1971 and undated (Box 1)
  - Pesticides
    - manuscripts, 1963-1979 (Box 1)
    - printed material, 1969-1974 and undated (Box 1)
  - Water Quality
    - Great Lakes, 1966-1971 and undated (Box 1)
    - Inland Lakes and Rivers, 1971-1975 and undated (Box 1)
    - Walled Lake (student papers), 1984, 11 reports in 1 expandable folder (Box 1)
  - West Michigan Environmental Action Council (printed material), 1970-1974 and undated (Box 1)